

Michael Rukundo Knabe

Project Manager with coding skills

Project Manager with a business mindset and a passion for satisfying customer needs. Certified Full Stack Web & App Developer with a huge interest in innovation and new technologies. Driven team-player with great communication skills and with previous experience within the tech industry through managing frontend, backend and design experts as well as third party technical service providers. Experienced in agile project-, product- and business development.

Contact Info

+49 173 3034474



mrknabe2@gmail.com

Personal Info

10245 Berlin, Germany 29.07.1990

Key Skills

Product Management Project Management Stakeholder Management

Problem Solving Responsive Design

JavaScript React.js

HTML5

CSS3

Node.js

Express

APIs

Software Testing

Tools

Jira, Trello Microsoft Office Salesforce / Hubspot Git and GitHub Console

Languages

VS Code

German: Native English: Excellent Spanish: Fluent

Interests

Sports: Running and Fitness Music: Acoustic Guitar

Education

06/2020 - 10/2020

Berlin

09/2016 - 10/2017 Lisbon / Copenhagen

09/2015 - 10/2017 Copenhagen

10/2011 - 02/2015 Cologne

09/2007 - 06/2010 Frechen

09/2006 - 06/2007 Shaftesbury

WBS CODING SCHOOL

Certificate in Full Stack Web and App Development

Master of Science in international Management CEMS – The Global Alliance in Management Education

Final Grade: A-

Master of Science in International Business

Copenhagen Business School

Final Grade: 1.7

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

University of Cologne Final Grade: 2.2

A-Levels (Abitur) Final Grade: 1.7

Year Abroad

Work Experience

12/2019 - 06/2020 Berlin

Senior Business Development Manager GoLiving

- Cooperation with large real estate companies short-term for leasing, mid-term for joint project development in Berlin, Cologne and Düsseldorf
- Identification of customer needs and development of suitable use cases
- Creation and continuous development of a corporate pitch deck and business development playbook

05/2019 - 10/2019 Berlin

Project Manager Mobility Apps - MaaS

Mobimeo GmbH (Deutsche Bahn AG)

- Strategic partner management: analysis of needs, definition of product scope & integration roadmap
- Consult partners on market entry strategy and comms strategy, train staff on products for customer service
- Management of external tech service providers
- Highlight project risks and develop mitigation options, ensure timely delivery and compliance with SLAs
- Manage various teams composed of product, engineering, design and market experts

11/2017 - 04/2019 Berlin

B2B Partnerships Manager - SaaS

Telefónica Germany NEXT GmbH (Minodes)

- Product Owner White Label: product development, market analysis, development and execution of channel strategy as well as first partners ahead of schedule
- Scaled up White Label to be major revenue channel
- Strategic development of partnerships throughout the entire process from acquisition and relationship building to closing, execution of roll-outs and cross-& upselling
- Planned and executed negotiations, onboardings and workshops with C-level executives
- Cross functional project management to ensure compliance with SLAs and make partners happy
- Promotion from SDR to Partnerships Manager

Internships & Volunteer Work

02/2016 - 05/2016 Copenhagen

Consultant

180 Degrees Consulting, Client: Non-Profit-Organization

- Analysed the client's organizational structure, employee incentives and fundraising strategy
- Developed and implemented new vision & mission statements, and a new organizational structure
- Created action plan to reach fundraising goals

12/2014 - 05/2015 Berlin

Business Developer

Rocket Internet SE (EatFirst)

- Set up, improved and executed operations processes
- Negotiations with business partners & suppliers
- Identification, analysis & reporting on operations KPIs

09/2013 - 12/2013 Cologne / Dortmund

Consultant

OSCAR GmbH, Client: Big Public Contractor

- Analysed the client's cost accounting processes and developed a new system for enhanced performance
- Carried out test runs of the concept
- Summary: The client's directors commissioned a follow-up project for companywide implementation

11/2011 - 09/2012 Cologne

Project Lead

AIESEC-Cologne (Student Society)

- Led a team of eight students
- Organized accommodation and internships in local NGOs for 20 volunteers from 13 nations

10/2010 - 06/2011 Madrid

Volunteer

Internationaler Bund e.V. – full-time

- Took a three months intensive Spanish course
- Worked six months as a volunteer in a kindergarten